Finding Aid for Woman’s Christian Temperance Union, Battle Creek Chapter records, 1874-1986
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Woman’s Christian Temperance Union, Battle Creek Chapter records 1874-1986
Woman’s Christian Temperance Union. Battle Creek Chapter.
2.5 linear feet
86318 Bj 2
Minutes of meetings, records of the Board of Trustees, minutes of the Red Ribbon Temperance Union, 1880-1882, scrapbook and printed material relating to activities of the Union.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was the gift of the Battle Creek chapter (donor no. 4656 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Battle Creek Woman's Temperance Union was established April 13, 1874. In December 1876, the group was formally organized as the Battle Creek Chapter of the Woman's Christian Temperance Union. Due to declining membership, the chapter disbanded November 21, 1986.
The record group documents the local activities of the W.C.T.U .includes minutes of regular meetings (1874-1986, with some gaps), minutes of the Board of Trustees (1907-1975, with some gaps), and minute book of the Red Ribbon Temperance Union, 1880-1882. Also included are record books of the treasurer, yearbooks with lists of officers, a scrapbook and assorted clippings, and reports of the chapter to the Michigan Department of the Treasury.
Subjects:
Battle Creek (Mich.); Prohibition--Michigan.; Red Ribbon Temperance Union.; Temperance--Michigan--Battle Creek.; Women--Michigan--Battle Creek--Societies and clubs.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Battle Creek.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union. Battle Creek Chapter (Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
- Minutes of Regular Meetings
  - 1874 and 1876-1879 (Box 1)
  - 1880-1886 (Box 1)
  - 1886-1891 (Box 1)
  - 1892-1895 (Box 1)
  - 1898-1901 (Box 1)
  - 1901-1905 (Box 1)
  - 1904-1905 (Box 1)
  - 1911-1916 (Box 1)
  - 1916-1919 (Box 1)
  - 1920-1922 (Box 1)
  - 1923-1925 (Box 1)
  - 1928-1930 (Box 1)
  - 1931-1938 (Box 1)
  - 1939-1949 (Box 1)
  - 1949-1954 (Box 1)
  - 1955-1958 (Box 1)
  - 1959-1962 (Box 1)
  - 1964-1969 (Box 1)
  - 1972-1975 (Box 1)
  - 1974-1982 (Box 2)
  - 1983-1986 (Box 2)
- Other Minute Books
  - Red Ribbon Temperance Union, 1880-1882 (Box 2)
    (men's auxiliary of the W.C.T.U.)
  - Board of Trustees of the Battle Creek W.C.T.U.
    - 1907-1911 (Box 2)
    - 1912-1916 (Box 2)
    - 1933-1942 (Box 2)
    - 1953-1956 (Box 2)
    - 1957-1975 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous
  - Treasurer's books, 1960-1976, 6 volumes (Box 2)
  - Assorted programs and yearbooks of the Battle Creek W.C.T.U. (Box 2)
  - Notebook of Mrs, Neubert, WCTU president (Box 2)
  - Assorted song books and other printed material (Box 3)
  - Newspaper clippings concerning the Battle Creek W.C.T.U. (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook concerning the Battle Creek W.C.T.U. (Box 3)
  - Financial miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Legal documents, including reports to Michigan Dept. of Treasury (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)